嗨
hi
我是Ryan kernietto
I'm Ryan kernietto
爵士框架 solid js的创造者
creator of the jazz framework solid js
的创造者，我很高兴能在这里参加v
and I'm excited to be here at v
comp上向大家介绍一下。
comp to tell you about it
这场讲座叫做 "入门"。
this talk is called getting started
这是以我们的启动模板的名字命名的
which plays off the name of our starter template
meta framer solid start
我不确定我们是否会在这里，如果它被打倒的话
and I'm not sure we'd be here if it went for beat
好吧
well
显然我们不会参加这个会议
obviously we wouldn't be at this conference
但我不知道我是否真的采取了冒险的做法
but I don't know if I did taken the plunge
试图创建这样一个雄心勃勃的项目
into trying to create such an ambitious project
坚实的开始
to solid start
所有的时间、深夜
all the hours the late nights
以及随之而来的维护负担
and the maintenance burden that comes with it
一个孩子
a kid
但说真的，我从来没有想过要做一个元框架
but seriously I never wanted to make a meta framework
如果你在github上看看
if you look on github
有一些几年前的问题
there are issues from a few years ago
我就坐在那里
where I sit as much
曾经
ever
beat改变了一切
beat changed everything
搏击已经能够
beat has been able
在网络平台上开发工具
to look at developing tools on the web platform
这就是我今天要讲的内容
and that's what I'm going to talk about today
但首先
but first
也许应该对solid js做一个简单的介绍
perhaps a brief introduction to solid js is in order
solid是什么？
what is solid
它是一个用于构建用户界面的爵士乐创作工具。
well it's a jazz crefamer for building user interfaces
和之前的很多产品一样
like so many before it
但让我们直接说说房间里的大象吧
but let's get right to the elephant in the room
我为什么要建立另一个javascript框架？
why would I build another javascript framework
这里有一段小历史
well a little history here
开发开始于2006年
development started back in 2006
为了便于理解，这一年spelt也被创建了。
for context that was the same year spelt was created
我的目标是把细粒度的反应性带回来
my goal was to bring back fine grain reactivity
类似于noco js
similar to noco js
我喜欢使用函数的模式
I love the patterns of using function
我喜欢使用函数组件的模式，并通过组成更小的
components and building uis from composing smaller
可重复使用的行为
reusable behaviors
但我从来没有真正地完全转向组件的生命周期。
never really made the full move to component lifecycles
他们让我想起了asp net webforms的太多东西。
they reminded me too much of asp net webforms
老实说，这让我很害怕
and honestly that terrified me
虚拟主机的性能要求让我感到困惑
the performance claims that the virtual dom confused me
也是如此
as well
而我知道反应性就是性能
and I knew reactivity to be performance
也许我们只是需要用不同的方式来攻击它。
maybe we just needed to attack it a different way
所以我就这么做了，而且对所有
so I did and for all
的
of
变得非常清楚的是
what became abundantly clear was that
对于所有的
for all the
组件架构带来的好处
good that component architectures had brought
我的意思是它们在现代
and I mean they are everywhere in modern
前端开发
front end development
我们已经
we've
完成了具有执行生命周期的代码组织
completed code organization with execution lifecycles
几乎所有的框架器
pretty much every framer
组件有运行时的考虑
components have runtime considerations
它们是我们的主要状态管理
they are our primary state management
有渲染器或一切
there are renderer or everything
而且这并不局限于虚拟主机
and this wasn't limited to the virtual dom
这对编译方案和非编译方案都是如此
it was true for compile solutions as non compile
严格的模板字词
tight template literals
2个虚拟域的单文件组件到最热的dsls
2 v dom single file components to the hottest dsls
所有东西都是自上而下运行的
everything just running top down
我明白了，这有一点谁在乎呢？
I get it there's a bit of who cares
但它影响了后面的每一个问题
but it informs every subsequent question
我做什么？
what do I memoize
我什么时候能把我用于全局状态的东西记下来？
when do I memoize what I use for global state
我如何分享反应性
how do I share reactivity
什么时候使用效果
when to use effect
缩略语的区别是什么？
what's the difference between reduction context
为什么会出现两次日志
why does this log twice
为什么这个愚蠢的东西一直在重新渲染
why does this stupid thing keep re rendering
这些都是主导对话的主题
these are topics that dominate the conversation
而实际上我更愿意谈论的是
and really I'd rather be talking about
几乎所有的事情
pretty much anything
有很多东西是可以解锁的
there are a lot of things that are just unlocked
当你改变
when you change
角度
the perspective
一点点
a little bit
我绝对可以用诗意来形容
and I can definitely wax poetic
关于反应性的力量
about the power of reactivity
它是如何声明性的和可组合的
how it's declarative and composable
它是如何帮助产生
how it helps produce
具有可重复使用行为的结构良好的代码
well structure code with reusable behaviors
而且是独立于任何组件系统的
and that are independent of any component system
甚至是如何通过一些基本的打印工具
even how with a few basic printives
你就可以实现你所希望的一切
you can do everything you could ever wish for
包括渲染
including rendering
而且其性能是我们从手工优化的vanilla javascript以来从未见过的
and with performance we haven't seen
的性能，这是自手工优化的vanilla javascript以来从未见过的。
since hand optimized vanilla javascript
但这不是我今天来的原因
but that's not why I'm here today
我在这里要谈的是另一种原始的东西
I'm here to talk about a different sort of primitive
那就是Beat平台上的插件的力量
and that is the power of plugins in the beat platform
以及它们对我来说是如何起到作用的
and how they are instrumental for me
做一个完整的
doing a complete one
80的观点
80 on my perspective
这是一个很大的问题，因为我是一个天生的拆包者
which is a lot because I am naturally an unbundler
我喜欢把东西拆开，改变界限
I like breaking stuff apart and shifting boundaries
我喜欢证明新的概念
I like proving new concepts
我喜欢证明新的概念，并倾向于把它留给别人来做最后的判断。
and tend to leave it to others to pass the final
判断
judgment on
什么是正确的方法，把它放在一起
what the right approaches to put it all together
所以
so
让我们看看为什么
let's look at why
殴打呈现给我的东西，我只是
beat present to me with something I just
不能轻易否定
couldn't easily dismiss
虽然它始于对预期结果的理解
while it starts with understanding desired outcomes
我知道自杀式渲染将是
I knew suicide rendering was going to be
事情走向的关键
key to where things were heading
在这一领域的许多创新
a lot of innovation in this space
是找到如何更好地利用
is finding how to better leverage
服务器与客户之间的差异
that server client divide
所以SSR需要成为软件包的一部分
so ssr needed to be part of the package
但与此同时
but at the same time
我并不愿意将单机版扔到公共汽车上
I was not willing to throw single pajaps under a bus
它需要同时支持两者，而且是无缝的
it needed to support both and seamlessly
从客户机到服务器的移动不应该感觉是一件苦差事
moving from client server shouldn't feel like a chore
当我们在做这件事的时候
and while we are at it
我们应该有所有的好处
we should have all the niceties
像文件系统的路由和
things like file system routing and
更加根深蒂固的数据获取模式和突变模式。
more ingrained patterns for data fetching a mutation
当然，它应该完全利用
and of course it should fully leverage
解决渲染中反应性的独特观点
solve a unique view of reactivity in rendering
并可在任何地方进行部署
and be deployable anywhere
在同一时间
at the same time
有一些事情我不想去处理
there were things I did not want to deal with
必须处理一堆配置，这可不是什么好玩的事。
having to wrangle a bunch of configuration is no fun
还有
also
我不想太有主见。
I didn't want to be too opinionated
好吧，意见可以是好的
well opinions can be good
首先，这需要为所有的事情工作。
first and foremost this needs to work for everything
而且我不想负责任
and I don't want to be responsible
至少要对人们的命运负责。
well at least that responsible for people's destiny
我从来不喜欢也不屑于使用元框架
I've never liked or bothered with meta frameworks
我自己
myself
所以当十亿项目时，我为什么要把它推给别人呢？
so when billion project why would I try to push that
在别人身上
on someone else
类似地
similarly
我不想提出一堆独家的想法
I didn't want to present a bunch of exclusive ideas
就像如果有人选择不使用这个项目
like if someone chose not to use this project
他们不应该觉得
they shouldn't feel
他们没有充分地利用固体
they aren't fully leveraging solid
而这一点真的延伸到了apis和库中
and this really extends to apis and libraries
理想情况下，你只是
ideally you just
使用生态系统中已经存在的所有东西
use everything that already existed in the ecosystem
我已经
I'd
我已经创建了一个嵌套的路由器，具有并行的
already created a nested router with parallelized
数据获取的嵌套式路由器，在我
data fetching long before I
就已经创建了一个具有并行数据获取功能的嵌套式路由器，在我想到要做一个元框架之前
ever thought of making a meta framework
老实说，我不希望有维护的负担
honestly I don't want the maintenance burden
你可以开始明白为什么我不太感兴趣了
you can start to see why I wasn't too interested
我们怎么可能得到
how do we possibly get
所有的好处，而没有坏处
all the upsides without the downsides
结果是这样的
well as it turns out
vitu kunta在一个更好的时机出现了
vitu kunta come out at a better time
最重要的是它提供了一个单一的配置
the big thing being it offered a single configuration
增加SSR
for adding ssr
这是我需要解决的第一个问题
this was the first problem I needed to solve
历史上，捆绑者并不关心
historically bundlers didn't concern themselves
这方面的问题
with this end
虽然你可以做一堆的配置
while you could make a bunch of configs
但这并不容易
it wasn't as easy
并不像运行一个带有标志的捆绑器那么简单
as just running a bundler with a flag
这一点很重要，因为在概念上意味着
and this is important because the conceptionally meant
我们有这种灵活性
that we had this flexibility
现在可以把这些东西放在彼此的上面
now to lay these things on top of each other
不需要额外的布线
without additional wiring
我们不需要对
we didn't need to be opinionated about
客户端与服务器的渲染
client versus server rendering
这一点可以从以下几个方面体现出来
and this is kind of exemplified
在
on
的插件系统中得到了体现。
the plugin system that beat has
它大致上是基于滚动的插件
it's based roughly on roll up plugins
而且你可以编写
and you can author
这些通用插件
these universal plugins
可以在整个平台上使用
that work across the whole platform
现在，魔鬼就在细节中
now the devil is in the details here
很多细微的差别，但V是堆叠的
a lot of nuance but v was stacked
有很多东西
with a lot of things
以使
to make
我们的生活变得更容易
our lives a lot easier
像glob导入来处理动态的文件传递
things like glob imports to handle dynamic file pass
你知道我们可以说是文件系统的路由
you know can we say file system routing
以及几乎是微不足道的能力
and almost the trivial ability
创建虚拟模块
to create virtual modules
以允许自定义编译将我们的模块分开。
to allow custom compilations to break our modules apart
这其中最好的部分
and the best part of this
只是一个共同的基础，只是一个插件
is just a common base of just a plugin
不需要一个实际的元框架
there's no need for an actual meta framework
只是一个V型插件的集合
just a collection of v plugins
和
and
我们意识到它几乎是立即像
we realize it's almost immediately like
我们只需要做这么少的事情
we had to do so little
来利用现有的生态系统
to leverage and existing ecosystem
像CSS这样的东西已经是它的一部分了
things like CSS were already part of it
虽然可能
and while maybe
会有一些坚实的特定功能
there'd be some solid specific features
我们为坚实的开始而建立的任何东西
anything we built for solid start
都可以在任何实体项目中使用
would work in any solid projects
同样，SOLIS tar也可以用于任何实体项目。
moreso solis tar could be used for any solid project
一切都是模块化的，就像现在这样
everything being modular as it is
这就解决了我2个避免清单上的一半事情
this is addresses half the things on my 2 avoid list
没有做任何事情
without doing anything
如果我们想让fossis从路由中出来，并与固体路由器一起工作
if we want fossis from routing that worked with
solid router
那就没有必要让solid start router成为现实。
there is no point in making solid start router
我们只需要把它作为一个v插件来构建
we'd just build it as a v plugin
我们把solid start作为源文件，而不是
we shift solid start as source instead of
预先建立
being pre built
而且它可以随处滑入。
and it just slides in everywhere
对可维护性来说是一个巨大的胜利
a huge win for maintainability
当然，这只是直接的好处。
but of course that's just the direct benefit
我们所发现的，因为它甚至比这更好
what we found since it is even better than that
有了这样一个模块化的方法
with such a modular approach
我们已经能够迅速测试各种想法
we've been able to test ideas rapidly
只需要再写一个V的插件就可以了
it's just a matter of writing another v plug in
而这种实验性的工作
and this sort of experimentation
对我们来说真的很重要
is really important to us
让我给你举个例子
let me give you an example
我们希望卖掉的是相同的客户端和服务器
we want sold to work the same client and server
并使用相同的库
and use the same libraries
就像固体船舵一样
like solids rudder
但是
but
肯定会有服务器的特定功能
there is definitely for server specific features
诸如获得自杀式道具和下一个或
things like get suicide props and next or
装载器和重混
loaders and remix
但我们并不想妥协
but we didn't want to compromise
而且我们想保留
and we wanted to keep
我们希望保留我们所期望的所有好处
all the benefits we'd come to desire
模块化和可组合的好处
from being modular and composable
Solid的模式
the pattern for solid
在过去的几年里，我们的模式是
the past several years has been
找到一个数据函数
to find a data function
附带给每个嵌套的路由部分
that has attached to each nested route section
并与拆分的代码平行运行
and runs in parallel to the code splitting
这让我们可以设置我们的资源
this lets us set up our resources
这就是
which are
基本上是一个特殊的信号，需要一个承诺
basically a special signal that takes a promise
并对其进行并行处理
and handle it in parallel
而这种
and this
机制工作得非常好，因为如果不去管它
mechanism worked really well because if left alone
它将在最初的ssr期间在服务器上获取信息
it will fetch on the server during initial ssr
然后
and then
在随后的导航中再次从浏览器中获取
again from the browser on subsequent navigation
但是，如果
but what if
我想总是在服务器上获取
I want to always fetch on the server
我们有一个想法，如果一个函数
well we had an idea what if a function
可以是
could be
在圆圈上，我是说任何函数
on the circle I mean any function
这并不是一个新的想法
this isn't a new idea
我们已经在blitz js中看到了这样的东西
we've seen stuff like this in blitz js
但如果我们能
but what if we could
利用节拍插件系统来实现这种
leverage beats plug in system to make this
遥远的选择行为
distant opt in behavior
就像文件系统的路由一样
like file system routing
我们可以测试一个想法，看看它是如何运作的
we could just test an idea and see how it would sit
立即看到这意味着我们可以保留
immediately saw that meant we could preserve
类型跨越边界
types across the boundary
这真的很不错
and this was really quite nice
我们可以在任何地方定义一个函数
we could just define a function anywhere
而你不需要担心
and you didn't need to worry
担心的问题。
both a url
或API
or API
网址也是
the url is also
可以作为该函数的一个属性
available as a property of that function
所以你可以在为处理url而设计的apis中使用它
so you can use it in apis designed to handle urls
我们实际上已经用这个
we've actually used this
来连接网络套接字等东西
to wire up things like web sockets
和服务器百分比防御
and server cent defense
但我们的收获是，我们突然有了
but the takeaway is suddenly we had
一个原始的方法来做
a primitive to do
以一种安全的方式进行网络通信，并且
network communication in a type safe way and
我们可以在任何地方使用它
we could use it anywhere
我们可以在任何文件中放置我们想要的服务器功能
we could put as many server functions we wanted in
任何文件
any file
因此，事实证明
so it turns out
我们可以直接把
we can just plug
这也是我们的资源
this right into our resources as well
突然间
suddenly
我们现在有了一个总是在服务器上运行的函数
we have a function now that always runs on the server
这很好，因为信条是这样构成的
it's nice how crematives compose like that
我们可以写一个包装器，把它清理一下
and we can write a wrapper to clean it up a little bit
当我们在工作时
and while we're in business
它比一个简单的水槽或加载器要大一些。
well it's a little bulkier than a simple a sink
函数或加载器
function or loader
我们在这里得到一些很酷的东西
we get a couple cool things here
比如我们资源的第一个参数
like the first argument to our resource
的第一个参数作为一个现金无效键
acting as a cash invalidation key
所以我们可以细化地使这些东西失效
so we can granularly invalidate these things
就像在图书馆里一样
the way one would with the libraries
参加该查询
attend to that query
我们还可以创建尽可能多的这些
we also can create as many of these
服务器数据或资源，只要我们想
server data or resources as we want
在给定的路线上
on the given route
并独立处理它们
and handle them all independently
而在另一边
and on the other side
我们希望对突变的行动
we wanted actions for mutations
和
and
同样
again
如果
if
使用这种服务器机制，我们可以在任何文件中划分它们
using this server mechanism we could divine them in
任何文件中的行动，只要我们愿意，任何文件中的行动都可以。
any file as many actions in any file as we wanted
我们基本上可以
we could basically
用这些来跟踪我们的突变的进展
use these to track the progress
我们的突变和管理
of our mutations and manage
乐观的更新
optimistic updates
默认情况下
by default
他们将只是刷新所有的日期
they'll just refresh all of the date
在当前路线上的所有日期
on the current route
但是
but
因为它们是细化的
because they're granular
它们也可以触发自己的失效键
they can also trigger their own invalidation keys
和
and
我有没有提到
did I mention
他们是逐步增强的表单专家，可以在
they expert progressively enhanced forms that work
不使用javascript
with no javascript
这一切都只是堆积在彼此的上面
this all just piles on top of each other
对
right
你可以定义
you can define
你可以在一个文件中定义任意多的这些动作
as many of these actions as you want in a file
因为它们只是服务器函数
as they are just server functions
而不觉得有什么限制，必须遵守
and not feel the restrictions of having to adhere
文件为基础的
to a file based
的API的限制，也不用担心无效时的过度获取。
API for local mutations or worrying about over
无效时的过度获取
fetching on invalidation
这有点像
it's sort of like a marriage between
某种程度上来说，它就像是remix和tanstack query之间的结合。
something like remix and tanstack query
我最喜欢的部分
my favorite part
我最喜欢的部分是，它
of the story is that it
是从一个原始的实验开始的
started from an experiment with a primitive
这基本上就是我们如何开发和巩固
that's basically how we develop and solid
我们创建一个基元
we create a primitive
并试着看它如何被使用
and try to see how it can be used
以确定其在世界的地位
to determine its place in the world
有时有明显的需要
sometimes there is obvious need
只能在核心部分处理
that can only be handled in the core
而它最终被
and it ends up
但在其他时候，我们会将几个月来的想法在我们的solid primeters repo中测试。
in the core but other times we test ideas from months
在我们的solid primeters repo中测试想法，然后
in our solid primeters repo and
你知道
you know
然后我们就会学到我们需要学习的东西
then we learn what the lessons we need to learn
人们一直在做一些不可思议的事情
people have been doing incredible things with
咿咿呀呀的，感觉就像编纂的一样。
babble with solid getting felt like compilations
和尝试新的dsl想法，因为
and try new dsl ideas because of how
因为它可以很容易地在上面构建
easy it's to build on top of
对我来说，当我看到维生素时
and for me the second I saw vit
我知道我们是
I knew we were
进入更多相同的东西
into more of the same
但如果你不相信的话
but if you aren't convinced
再举一个例子
one more example
想给你看一个
want to show you an
我们现在正在进行的实验
experiment we are working on right now
在此向Nikilseiroff致以崇高的敬意
a huge shoutout to nikilseiroff here
他把这些东西放在一起，使这个演示成为可能
who put together the pieces make this demo possible
我将演示一个应用程序
I'm going to demo an app
我太熟悉了
that I am all too familiar with
老黑客新闻演示
the old hacker news demo
如果你还没有看到坚实的开始
and if you haven't seen solid start
它基本上是
it's essentially
只是一个V项目
just a v project
你看，这里有一个V的配置，我们只是
you see there's a v config right here and we just
插上我们的
plug in our
实体插件
solid plug in
和
and
我们非常
we were very
我们很容易就能把它倒在
easily able to actually just pour it over
当我们现有的
when our existing
的客户端模板
v templates for client side
因为我们所需要做的就是
because all we need to do really was
把存在于我们read项目中的索引HTML
take the index HTML
存在于我们的阅读项目中
that exists in our read project
并将其转换为这个gsx的东西
and convert it to this gsx thing
这里有一些细节
there's some details here
比如
like
我们的路由器使用
our router uses
一个路由文件来
a file of routes to
暗示它要使用文件系统路由
suggest that it wants to use file system routing
一旦到位
once in place
我们基本上就有了一个路由器
we basically just have a router
而我们唯一需要做的其他小调整是
and the only other little tweak we had to do really was
我们的数据功能以前是在单独的文件中的
our data functions which used to be in separate files
现在可以直接放在文件的顶部了
can now be just at the top of the file
这与我们之前所看到的非常相似
and this is very similar to what we were looking at
在
on the
前面的幻灯片
previous slides
所以让我们来试试我们的例子
so let's try our example in action
开始我们的服务器
start off our server
这只是一个典型的黑客新闻应用
and this is just your typical hacker news app
我们只是在它的客户端进行导航
we just navigate around its client rendered
客户端导航的
client navigated
基本上有一些故事列表页面
and there's basically some story listing pages
然后你可以进入具体的故事
and then you can go into the specific story
如果你愿意的话，还可以折叠评论
and collapse the comments if you wish
为了向你展示它是由客户端渲染的
and just to show you that it's client rendered
让我们看一下网络标签
let's look at the network tab
当我加载这个时，你会看到
when I load this what you'll see
是
is
初始HTML加载一些javascript和CSS
initial HTML loading some javascript and CSS
然后你会看到，故事和
and then you'll see that the storiesand the
数据API领同时发生
data API collar getting happening at the same time
然后它的客户端渲染
and then it client renders
事实上，你可以看到，HTML bcent
and in fact you can actually see that the HTML bcent
有一个空的主体
has an empty body
它是一个非常典型的单页应用程序
and it's a pretty typical single page app
从那里
from there
当我们导航到一个新的页面时
when we navigate to a new page
我们将看到的基本上是
what we'll see is essentially
新的javascript和对数据的抓取
the new javascript and the fetch for the data
并行进行的
sue that page happening in parallel
这都要归功于solidsrider。
and this is all thanks to solidsrider
这里没有什么新东西
there's nothing new here
但是
but
但如果能在服务器上渲染这个页面，使之成为一个新的页面，那就更好了。
perhaps it would be nice to
服务器渲染这个页面，所以
server render this page so
我只是要进入我们的节拍配置
I'm just going to go into our beat config
为我们的插件和迪斯科
for our plug in and disco
服务器 ssr
server ssr
true
而现在
and now
快速建立
with a quick build
而我正在做
and I'm doing
在这里进行生产构建
the production build here
而不是只做开发模式
instead of just doing dev mode
因为我真的想展示一下这些资源
because I actually want to show off the resources
beat有很好的hmr
beat has great hmr
我们可以看到当我重新加载页面时
we can see when I reload the page
这
that
现在大部分的工作
now the majority of the work
实际上发生在服务器上
actually happens on the server
当它获取数据的时候
while it fetches the data
然后所有其余的javascript
and then all the rest of the javascript
加载和并行
loads and parallel
我们实际上可以看到，当我们看一看
and we can actually see when we look at the
渲染的页面
rendered page
现在我们有一个完整的页面
and now we have a full page
包含我们所有的故事列表
that contains all our story listings
和
and
序列化的Jason，我们需要显示它们
serialized Jason that we need to display them
但同样从这里
but again from here
当我们浏览的时候
when we navigate around
这也是我们已经习惯的客户端路由。
this is the same client side routing that we've
我们已经习惯了
come to accustom to
而这是一个非常典型的
and this is a pretty typical
你在大多数元框架中都能找到
that you find in most meta frameworks
但
but
我们认为
we thought well
为什么要停在这里
why stop here
我已经看到了非常酷的事情
I've been seeing really cool things
在框架中做的事情
being done in framers
像Astro和Fresh
like astro and fresh
所以我们就想
so we're like
会发生什么，如果我们
what happens if we
试图使
tried to make
它是一个多页的应用程序，有互动的岛屿，而不是
it a multi page app with interactive islands instead
所以这是一个例子，我们只是玩了一下
so this an example of us just playing around
这是个例子，我们只是在玩一个B型插件，看看我们能做什么。
with a b plug and seeing what we could do
所以
so
我们需要做什么来使这些
what we need to do to make those
评论崩溃仍然是互动的，只是
comment collapsing still interactive is just
有一种方式将他们定义为一个岛屿
have a way of defining them as an island
并作为一种实验
and kind of as an experiment
再次使用这个v插件
again using this v plugin
我们意识到，如果我们能将
we realized what if we could just
导入
import
我们的组件
our component
有点类似于我们导入懒人组件的方式
kind of similar to how we import lazy components
而其中一个是
and which one is
它是一个切换器
it's a toggle
和
and
将其定义为一个岛
define it as an island
而我们实际上在这里做的是
and what we're actually doing here is
我们正在寻找这个
we're looking for this
而实际上我们正在做一个编译器交换
and actually we're doing a compiler swap
这影响了构建过程
that affects the build process
再次感谢
again thanks to
如果我现在运行这个
and if I run this now
和
and
启动
start
之前我们看到的是
previously we were looking at
在我们的页面上有大约15千字节的JavaScript
about 15 kilobytes of javascript on our page
以便基本上加载
in order to basically load
所有的交互性并进行渲染
all the interactivity and do the rendering
这在客户端和服务器上的渲染是一样的
and this is the same on client and server rendering
但在这个新的岛屿模式中，当我们刷新页面时
but in this new islands mode when we refresh the page
我们就不需要那么多的JavaScript了
we don't need nearly as much javascript
而当我们进入我们的故事时
and when we go into our story
只需要5kB的javascript就足够了
it's literally just 5kB of javascript just enough
来触发我们的岛屿的水化
to trigger the hydration of our islands
正如你所看到的，这仍然有效
and as you can see this still works
所以我们有同样的互动性和同样的体验
so we have the same interactivity and same experience
在大约1
at about 1/3 of the cost in javascript
null
but again
we have this whole platform available to us
null
what else can we do
well we thought
null
wouldn't it be cool if we could do islands and
still have
null
maybe
quiet side routing
null
because sorry I didn't show it off here with the island
as you navigate around you can see this refresh
null
it's a full page refresh
can just show this really easily
null
we expand out some elements here
we navigate it's re rendering the whole page
null
this is fine and we still get the benefitsof being
having less javascript and great page
null
little performance
but so again just
null
through v plugins
what if we could
null
kind of try to see if we could get the best
but both worlds
null
and
yeah
null
we could load maybe 5kB of javascript initially
but
null
now when we go into our story
we
null
get the extra javascript for that toggle
which still works but
null
but as I'm navigating around
we're just fixed at 6kB of javascript
而我们得到的是客户端的路由，整个
and we were getting client side routing the whole
实际上，这里发生的事情是，我们正在换掉
what's actually happening here is we're swapping out
变化的那部分页面
the portion of the page that changes
头部永远不会重新呈现
the header never rerenders
所以当我们到这里时
so when we go here
我们只是把它换掉了
we're just swapping it out
这是一个嵌套的
this is a nested
服务器渲染的客户端路由器
server rendered client router
老实说
honestly
这里有很多可以玩的东西
there's just so much here to play with
我很兴奋
that I'm pretty excited
我的意思是，我不能等到有人
I mean I can't wait till someone
认识到有了服务器功能
realizes that with server functions
它可以做一个
it can kind of do a
坚实的起步阶段
solid start inception
老实说
honestly the
这里的界限似乎是无止境的
the boundaries seem endless here
这就是我要说的全部内容
so that's what all I have to say
我太懒了，没有再做一张幻灯片
I was too lazy to make another slide
但
but
主要是因为它真的很难超越这一张
mostly because it's really hard to top this one
以同样的方式
in the same way
坚实的开端将是基础
solid start is going to be the foundation
为未来的坚实应用打下基础
for solid applications in the future
节拍在使
beat has been instrumental in making
坚实的开始成为现实
solid start a reality
我本来想告诉你这是一个疯狂的尝试
I would have told you it would be crazy to take this on
之前，但
before but
现在我无法想象
now I can't picture
不能够给人们
not being able to give people
这样有价值的工具来帮助他们制作最好的网络应用程序。
such valuable tools to help them making the best web
应用
applications
我想这个讲座不能被称为入门
I suppose this talk can't be called getting started
讲座
without
向大家展示如何开始使用这一切
showing you all how to get started with all this
开始
start
mpm和knit
mpm and knit
固体
solid
就是这样
that's it
你就可以
and you'll be
就可以在创建
on your way to creating
下一代的网站和应用程序
the next generation of websites and applications
谢谢你，V
so thank you v
并感谢你们所有人
and thank you all